<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">Upchar</string>

    <string name="asthma"> 1 Help the person to sit up and remain calm.\n
        2) Assist the person in using their prescribed inhaler, if they have one.\n
        3) Encourage the person to take slow, deep breaths.\n
        4) Loosen any tight clothing that may be restricting their breathing.\n
        5) If the persons symptoms do not improve, call emergency services or take them to the nearest hospital for further treatment.</string>
    <string name="burns">1) Remove the source of heat or flames and move the person away from danger.\n
        2) Cool the burned area with cool water for at least 10–20 minutes to reduce pain and swelling.\n
        3) Cover the burn with a clean, dry, non-adhesive dressing or cloth to protect it from infection.\n
        4) If the burn is severe, seek medical attention immediately.\n
        5) If the persons clothing is stuck to the burn, do not try to remove it. Cut around the burned area and remove any loose clothing.</string>
    <string name="choking">1) Ask the person if they are choking and if they need help.\n
2) perform the Heimlich maneuver by standing behind the person and place hand above persons navel than thrust both hands backwards into their stomach\n
3) If the person is unable to perform the Heimlich maneuver, lean the person forward. Administer up to 5 forceful blows between the person’s shoulder blades with the heel of your hand\n
4) If the person becomes unconscious, lower them to the ground and begin CPR.\n
5)perform chest compressions by pushing hard and fast in the center of the chest. If you are trained and able, perform rescue breaths.</string>
    <string name="diabetes">1) If the person is conscious and able to swallow, provide them with a sugary drink or candy to raise their blood sugar level.\n
2) If the person is unconscious or unable to swallow, do not give them anything to eat or drink and seek medical attention immediately.\n
3) Check the persons vital signs and monitor their breathing and level of responsiveness.\n
4) If the person has a glucagon kit, administer it as directed.\n
5) If the persons condition worsens or they become unresponsive, call emergency services or take them to the nearest hospital for further treatment.</string>
    <string name="electrical_injury">1) Check for the source of the electrical shock. Look to see if the victim is still in contact with the source. Don’t touch them.\n
2) turn off the electrical current. Separate the victim from the source with non-conducting material that you may use.\n
3) if victim is not responding to questions or reacting to pain perform CPR.\n
4)perform chest compressions by pushing hard and fast in the center of the chest. If you are trained and able, perform rescue breaths\n
5) Identify burned areas. rinse the burns with cool water. Cover the burn.</string>
    <string name="fever">1) Help the person to rest and stay hydrated by drinking plenty of fluids, such as water or herbal tea.\n
2) Use a cool compress or sponge to lower the persons body temperature.\n
3) If the person is uncomfortable, provide them with over-the-counter medication to reduce fever, such as acetaminophen or ibuprofen, if it is safe to do so.\n
4) Encourage the person to wear lightweight clothing and to stay in a cool, well-ventilated room.\n
5) If the persons fever persists or they have other symptoms, such as difficulty breathing or a rash, seek medical attention.</string>
    <string name="fracture">1) Keep the injured area still and Do not try to realign the bone or push it back into place.\n
2) Apply a cold compress or ice pack to the injured area to reduce swelling and pain.\n
3) If the fracture is an open fracture cover the wound with a clean cloth or bandage to prevent infection.\n
4) if victim is not responding to questions or reacting to pain perform CPR.\n
5)perform chest compressions by pushing hard and fast in the center of the chest. If you are trained and able, perform rescue breaths.</string>
    <string name="headache">1) Help the person to rest in a quiet, dark room.\n
2) Offer the person a cool compress or ice pack to the affected area.\n
3) If the person has medication for their headaches, help them to take it if they need it and if it is safe to do so.\n
4) Encourage the person to take slow, deep breaths and to relax their muscles.\n
5) If the persons headache does not improve or if they have other symptoms such as a fever or neck stiffness, seek medical attention.</string>
    <string name="heart_attack">1) Have the person sit or lie down and loosen any tight clothing.\n
2) Give the person a chewable aspirin.\n
3) If the person becomes unresponsive, begin CPR.\n
4) perform chest compressions by pushing hard and fast in the center of the chest.\n
5)  If you are trained and able, perform rescue breaths</string>
    <string name="near_drowning">1)If the person is breathing, place them on their side in the recovery position to prevent choking or vomiting.\n
2) Monitor the persons breathing and level of responsiveness until medical help arrives.\n
3) If the person is not breathing, begin CPR.\n
4) perform chest compressions by pushing hard and fast in the center of the chest.</string>
    <string name="nose_bleeding">1) Help the person to sit down and lean forward slightly to avoid swallowing blood.\n
2) Pinch the soft part of the persons nose with a clean cloth or tissue and apply gentle pressure for at least 10-15 minutes.\n
3)Apply a cold compress to the persons nose to constrict blood vessels and reduce bleeding.\n
4) If bleeding persists or the person feels faint or dizzy, seek medical attention.\n
5) Encourage the person to avoid blowing their nose or picking at any scabs for at least 24 hours.</string>
    <string name="panic_attack">1) Stay calm and encourage the person to do the same.\n
2) Help the person to sit down and take slow, deep breaths.\n
3) Reassure the person that they are not in danger and that the panic attack will pass.\n
4) Avoid making any sudden or loud noises that may startle the person.\n
5) If the person has medication for their panic attacks, help them to take it if they need it and if it is safe to do so.</string>
    <string name="poisioning">1) If the person has come into contact with poison on their skin. rinse the affected area with water for at least 15 minutes.\n
2)If the person has ingested poison, do not induce vomiting or give them anything to eat or drink, including medication, unless instructed to do so by medical professionals.\n
3) If the person is unconscious but breathing, place them in the recovery position on their side with their head supported.\n
4) Provide as much information about the poison as possible to emergency responders, including the type of poison.</string>
    <string name="snakebite">1) Keep the person calm and immobile to slow the spread of venom.\n
2) Remove any jewelry or tight clothing that could restrict circulation in case of swelling.\n
3) Keep the affected limb below heart level to reduce the flow of venom.\n
4) Find a wrap thats clean and dry. Cover the snakebite. If possible, tightly wrap a pressure bandage around the wound.\n
5) Do not attempt to suck out the venom, cut the bite area, or apply a tourniquet</string>
    <string name="stomache">1) Help the person to rest in a comfortable position.\n
2) Offer the person clear fluids, such as water or herbal tea, to keep them hydrated.\n
3) Avoid giving the person solid foods until their stomachache subsides.\n
4) Apply a warm compress to the persons stomach to provide relief.\n
5) If the stomachache persists or the person has other symptoms, such as vomiting or fever, seek medical attention.</string>
    <string name="stroke">1) Note the time when symptoms first appeared and share this with the emergency responders.\n
2) Keep the person still and comfortable, with their head and shoulders slightly elevated.\n
3) If the person is unconscious but breathing, place them in the recovery position on their side with their head supported.\n
4) Do not give the person anything to eat or drink, including medication, unless instructed to do so by medical professionals.</string>
</resources>